Guide to the Dorothy M. Proud papers, 1938-1985.
Proud, Dorothy M. papers, 1938-1985.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dorothy M. Proud papers, 1938-1985.
23-15-2186
Dorothy M. Proud
.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers relating to the design of a multi-purpose three-compartment sink for use in community kitchens and nursing homes. Also papers pertaining to a course survey done in the Department of Institution Management, and correspondence about establishing the Dorothy Proud Lectureship in nutrition.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Institution Management.
Dorothy Proud received her B.A. from the Western Reserve University in Cleveland, Ohio and her M.A. in administrative dietetics at the University of Minnesota in 1930. She worked at Western University Hospital's Department of Dietetics as the assistant director of the department and director of the dietetic internship program before joining the faculty of the College of Home Economics in 1942 as an extension specialist in Institution Management. She was appointed assistant professor in 1946 and associate professor in 1949.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers relating to the design of a multi-purpose three-compartment sink for use in community kitchens and nursing homes. Also papers pertaining to a course survey done in the Department of Institution Management, and correspondence about establishing the Dorothy Proud Lectureship in nutrition.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Proud, Dorothy M.; Cornell University. College of Home Economics. Department of Institution Management.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Thesis and term paper, 1929, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Personal correspondence, 1938-1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Proud, 1948-1949, 1942-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Sabbatic, 1951, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Proud - personal, 1956, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- School lunch - design criteria, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Proud - University of Wisconsin, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Wisconsin appointment, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Work simplification - Tues. & Thurs., 9-11, Spring, 1964, Kathryn Meekers, Rm. G20 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Sabbatic leave ideas, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Sabbatic, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- American Dietetic Assoc., 50th Annual Mtg., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Material re: survey in the Department of Institution Management, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "Special Sinks", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Equipment Design and Handicap, prepared by Rose C. Steidl, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Dohrman - Mr. E.E. Ritchie, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Commercially available sinks with list prices, dimensions of H.H. Sink studies, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Sink, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Drawing and letter, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Project S898 - The Design of a Multipurpose 3 Compartment Sink ..., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Project S898 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- A Multi-Purpose, 3 Compartment Institutional Sink (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Memos re: #898 funds and handbook, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Recent correspondence: Merrifield, Galloway, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Article for Fall bulletin of NYS Diabetic Association, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Letter from E. Carey about sink, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Faucet information, and statement of need for Chicago Faucet catalog, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Appointments (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Retirement (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Training and employment history (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Community buildings - food service equipment (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Mailing lists (Box 2, Folder 14)